Guide to the Berkeley Divinity School Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Berkeley Divinity School records
1854-2010
RG 216
Yale University Divinity School Library
80
80 boxes
These are the official archives of Berkeley Divinity School, a seminary of the Episcopal Church, which affiliated with Yale Divinity School in 1971.
Berkeley Divinity School
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by Berkeley Divinity School
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research by permission of the Dean of Berkeley Divinity School.
Biographical / Historical
Berkeley Divinity School's origins go back to the Anglo-Irish bishop and philosopher George Berkeley, who dreamed of building a seminary in the New World that would express the breadth of the Anglican tradition in new environs. While Berkeley's vision never materialized in his own lifetime, he left his farm in Newport, Rhode Island, and library of theological books to the youthful Yale College in 1733. These books, which formed a core of Yale's early collection, played a significant role in the growth of Anglicanism in America. Yale became one of the earliest accepted places for Anglican candidates for ministry in America to read theology, graduating such pioneers as Samuel Seabury, the first bishop of the Episcopal Church.
In 1854, Bishop John Williams of Connecticut saw the need for a new seminary to be a mediating influence during a time of theological division in the Episcopal Church. Williams founded the Berkeley Divinity School in Middletown, Connecticut, naming it after George Berkeley, as a place where students from the various streams of Anglicanism could learn, worship, live and minister alongside one another. Bishop Williams, who later became Presiding Bishop of the Episcopal Church, served as Dean of the School himself until 1899. As indicated by the School's motto, in illa quae ultra sunt ("into the regions beyond"), the seminary has for over 150 years prepared clergy, educators and other leaders to serve throughout the church as part of its mission of "restoring all people to unity with God and each other in Christ."
In 1928, Dean William Palmer Ladd moved Berkeley Divinity School to New Haven, adjacent to the campus of Yale University, both to make advantage of the resources of the University and to immerse the students in the new social reality of the industrial city. A pioneer of the Liturgical Movement in the Episcopal Church, Dean Ladd envisioned a vibrant sacramental life nourishing an ongoing commitment to social justice that continues to shape Berkeley's mission to this day. Additional documentation regarding Dean Ladd is available in the William Palmer Ladd Papers, YDSL Record Group 136.
As a seminary of the Episcopal Church, Berkeley affiliated with Yale Divinity School in 1971, making it the only Episcopal seminary to be fully associated with a major research institution such as Yale University. While Berkeley retains its distinctive Anglican identity and retains an independent board of trustees and administration, its students are admitted by and fully enrolled as members of Yale Divinity School.
Scope and Contents
The archives of the Berkeley Divinity School have been organized according to its governance structure and activities.
Series IV, Student records, can be viewed only with written permission from the Dean of Berkeley Divinity School.
Arrangement
I. Deans.
II. Trustees.
III. Faculty & Staff.
IV. Students.
V. Alumni.
VI. Academics & School Life.
VII. History.
VIII. Publications.
IX. Related Organizations.
Theology -- Study and teaching -- Episcopal Church; Berkeley Divinity School
- Deans, Series I
  - John Binney 1899-1908
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Writings About (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (picture) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - William Palmer Ladd 1917-1941
    - Correspondence
      - A-W, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 4-21)
      - A-Z, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 22-27)
      - A-Z, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 28-34)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - J.B. Sill, 1890s (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Writings/Class notes
      - Contributions to publications (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Addresses and Contacts (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Articles – Misc (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "The Christian Attitude..." (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - The American Churches and the International Situation (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - "Guide to Christian Living", Correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Prayer Book Interleaves (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Prayer Book Interleaves – Correspondence A-Z, misc (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
      - Class notes (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Misc. Writings (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - About Ladd
      - Appreciation of Ladd (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Socialist Conflict (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Misc. About (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Ladd Memorial contributions (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Ladd Memorial (book) (Box 2)
      - Ladd Installation (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Charles Hedrick (Acting Dean), 1941-1942
    - Writings (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - About (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lawrence Rose, 1942-1947
    - Correspondence
      - With Bishop Budlong (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - B-Z (Box 2, Folder 56-70)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Installation (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Documents on Resignation (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Writings by and About (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Percy Urban, 1947-1957
    - Correspondence
      - A-Z (Box 2, Folder 74-76)
      - Bishop Budlong (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Letters to Alumni 1970 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - 1970 Kaulfus Letter (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Sample Letters to Alumni (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Writings
      - Theological Education Sermon, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Information About (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Dean Search Process, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Personal File (Box 2, Folder 85)
      - Installation (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Death (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Richard H. Wilmer 1957-1969
    - Correspondence
      - A-Z (Box 3, Folder 88-89)
      - Nuts, Bolts, and Oddments (Box 3, Folder 90)
      - With and Regarding (pre-dean years) (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Writings
      - Sermons (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - "Theological Education at BDS" (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Installation (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - Resignation (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Robert H. Anderson (Acting Dean), 1969-1970
    - Faculty Years (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Associate and Acting Dean Years (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - J. Michael Allen, 1970-1976
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous - Internal/External (Box 3, Folder 98-98c)
      - With Trustees (Box 3, Folder 98d-98e)
      - Hildebrand, William S. (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - Letters to School (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - Presiding Bishop Allin (Box 3, Folder 99b)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Installation (Box 3, Folder 100-101)
      - Resignation/Search Process (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - Personal File (Box 3, Folder 103-104)
      - Re. Ordination of Women (Box 3, Folder 104b-104c)
      - Re. Berkeley Crisis/Merger -Future of Berkeley (Box 4, Folder 105-106)
  - Rowan Greer (Acting Dean), 1976-1977
    - Definition of Director (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Letters to Seminary Deans (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Definition of Dean (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Search Committee 1 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Memos from Whiteman, Greer (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Search Committee 2 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Charles Clark, 1977-1982
    - Correspondence
      - A-B (Box 4, Folder 113-114)
      - Campbell, Dr. Barbara (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - Campbell, the Rev. Donald (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - Campbell, Rev. Thomas G. (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Carr, Rev. John (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - Carr, Oscar C., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 119-120)
      - Diocese of Central Philippines (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - Chandler, Gail (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - Chase, A. Elizabeth (Box 4, Folder 123)
      - Chater, The Rev. E. Walter (Box 4, Folder 124)
      - Cheney, Francis (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - Child, Rev. Kendrick (Box 4, Folder 125b)
      - Church of England (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - Clague, James (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - Cipolla, Rev. Richard G. (Box 4, Folder 128)
      - Clark, Henry T., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - Clarke, The Rt. Rev. Sundar (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - Corbiere, John (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - Cuthbert, Rev. John S. (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Dorsch, Kenneth John (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - Drew, Alaric James (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Dumalagen, Rev. Narcisco (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - Du Toit, Prof. Daniel A. (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - Eisenmenger, David J. (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - England, Rev. John C. (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - Englund, Mr. Steven (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Episcopal Radio and Television Foundation (Box 4, Folder 139b)
      - Evans, Robert A. (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - Evans, Rev. Robert (Box 4, Folder 141)
      - Everist, Rev. Burton, Rev. Norma (Box 4, Folder 142)
      - Fairweather, Prof. Eugene (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - Feliciano, Francisco (Box 4, Folder 144)
      - Fisher, Thomas (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - Fitch, Rev. James (Box 4, Folder 146)
      - Frisch, Floyd C. (Box 4, Folder 147)
      - Foster, Rev. Leon (Box 4, Folder 148)
      - French, Nancy (Box 4, Folder 149)
      - Gary, Rev. Richard E. (Box 4, Folder 150)
      - Gendreau, Rev. Robert A. (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - Gooden, Rt. Rev. Robert B. (Box 4, Folder 152)
      - Goodrow, Rev. John H. (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - Gramley, Thomas S. (Box 5, Folder 154)
      - Gres-Gayer, Rev. Jacques (Box 5, Folder 155)
      - Grigsby, Rev. Philip (Box 5, Folder 156)
      - Hall, Charles E., Jr. (Box 5, Folder 157)
      - Hall, Richard H. (Box 5, Folder 158)
      - Heischman, Daniel R. (Box 5, Folder 159)
      - Henderson, Robert S. (Box 5, Folder 160)
      - Hines, Rt. Rev. John E. (Box 5, Folder 162)
      - Hodgson, Mr. Robert (Box 5, Folder 163)
      - Holliger, Rev. John C. (Box 5, Folder 164)
      - Holmes, Urban (Box 5, Folder 165)
      - Hsaio, Dr. Ching-fen (Box 5, Folder 166)
      - Huang, Rev. Po-Ho (Box 5, Folder 167)
      - ICUIS (Box 5, Folder 168)
      - Jenkins, Sister Mary (Box 5, Folder 169)
      - Jones, David (Box 5, Folder 170)
      - Klemmt, Pierce (Box 5, Folder 171)
      - Krueger, John W. (Box 5, Folder 172)
      - Krumm, Rt. Rev. John (Box 5, Folder 173)
      - LaFollette, Rev. Melvin W. (Box 5, Folder 174)
      - Lawson, Rev. William B. (Box 5, Folder 175)
      - Low, Rev. William H. (Box 5, Folder 176)
      - Lund, Rev. G. Clarence (Box 5, Folder 177)
      - Lunetta, Rev. Donald (Box 5, Folder 178)
      - Macquarrie, Rev. Dr. John (Box 5, Folder 179)
      - Mann, Rt. Rev. Michael (Box 5, Folder 180)
      - Marrett, The Rev. Michael M. (Box 5, Folder 181)
      - McElroy, Rev. Gary A. (Box 5, Folder 182)
      - Melinsky, Canon M. A. H (Box 5, Folder 183)
      - Menuez, Mr. Barry (Box 5, Folder 184)
      - Middleton, Ms. Eloise L. (Box 5, Folder 185)
      - Morgan, Rev. Robert (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - Moser, Frederick (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - Morrison, Douglas (Box 5, Folder 188)
      - Nacpil, Rev. Emerito P. (Box 5, Folder 189)
      - Neill, Rt. Rev. Stephen (Box 5, Folder 190)
      - Neisheim, Deborah (Box 5, Folder 191)
      - Nelson, The Rev. J. Reed Peter (Box 5, Folder 192)
      - Norman, The Rev. Peter M. (Box 5, Folder 193)
      - Nurser, Rev. Canon John S. (Box 5, Folder 194)
      - Obert, Edward J. (Box 5, Folder 195)
      - Okoth, Rt. Rev. Yona (Box 5, Folder 196)
      - Osborne, Ernest (Box 5, Folder 197)
      - Parker, Everett (Box 5, Folder 198)
      - Potter, Barrie V. (Box 5, Folder 199)
      - Powers, Jeanne Audrey (Box 5, Folder 200)
      - Prentis, John Brook III (Box 5, Folder 201)
      - Pusey, Dr. Nathan M. (Box 5, Folder 202)
      - Ramsey, Rt. Rev. Michael (Box 5, Folder 203)
      - Randles, Rev. David C (Box 5, Folder 204)
      - Reed, Bruce (Box 5, Folder 205)
      - Reynolds, Stanley (Box 5, Folder 206)
      - Richards, Rt. Rev. David E. (Box 5, Folder 207)
      - Richardson, Mr. Lunsford Jr. (Box 5, Folder 208)
      - Riggs, The Rev. Lee (Box 5, Folder 209)
      - Rioch, Margaret J. (Box 5, Folder 210)
      - Risley, Mr. Russell (Box 5, Folder 211)
      - Rosborough Rev Bonnie A (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Saayman, Dr. Willem (Box 5, Folder 213)
      - Sargent, The Rev. Thomas (Box 5, Folder 214)
      - Schweitzer, Albert (about) (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - Armstrong, J. Sinclair (Box 5, Folder 216)
      - Skillman, John (Box 5, Folder 217)
      - Smith, Mrs Llewellyn P. (Box 5, Folder 218)
      - Stetson, Charles P. Jr (Box 5, Folder 219)
      - Stevenson, Rev. Hugh (Box 5, Folder 220)
      - Sugise, Professor Yutake (Box 5, Folder 221)
      - Sullivan, Sister Mary (Box 5, Folder 222)
      - Tavel, Ron (Box 5, Folder 223)
      - Te Selle, Sallie (Box 5, Folder 224)
      - Toon, Rev. Peter (Box 5, Folder 225)
      - Trowbridge, C. Rachel (Box 5, Folder 226)
      - Trustees (Box 5, Folder 227)
      - Tull, Rev. Alan C. (Box 5, Folder 228)
      - Turner, Rev. Gregory (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Tweedy (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Wagner, Edward (Box 6, Folder 231)
      - Wales, Caroline (Box 6, Folder 232)
      - Walmsley, Bishop Arthur (Box 6, Folder 232b)
      - Wangoya, The Rev. W. Sange (Box 6, Folder 233)
      - Ward, David J. (Box 6, Folder 234)
      - Weatherly, Rev. Canon Bruce (Box 6, Folder 235)
      - Weatherby, Gary (Box 6, Folder 236)
      - Wen Han, Kiang (Box 6, Folder 237)
      - West, Robert B. (Box 6, Folder 238)
      - Westerhoff, John H. III (Box 6, Folder 239)
      - Westhorp, The Rev. Canon Clifford S. (Box 6, Folder 240)
      - Wheland, Rev. Peter H. (Box 6, Folder 241)
      - Williams, Dr. Carol (Peterson) (Box 6, Folder 242)
      - Woods, Rev. Robin W. (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - Yoder, Bruce (Box 6, Folder 244)
      - Younger, Rev. George (Box 6, Folder 245)
      - Zabriskie, Rev. George II (Box 6, Folder 246)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 246b)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Installation (Box 6, Folder 247)
      - Canonical Residence (Box 6, Folder 248)
      - 1979 Statement (Box 6, Folder 249)
      - Photo (Box 6, Folder 250)
      - Reports/Studies (Box 6, Folder 251)
      - Articles (Box 6, Folder 252)
      - Ordination of Women (Box 6, Folder 252b)
      - Advisees (Box 6, Folder 253)
      - Case Studies in Ministry (Box 6, Folder 254)
      - Christian Witness (Box 6, Folder 255)
      - Clark, Noyce and Holmer Course, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - James Annand, 1982-1991
    - Correspondence: alphabetical sequence
      - A-E (Box 6, Folder 257-261)
      - Episcopal Church Center (Box 6, Folder 261b)
      - F-P (Box 6, Folder 262-269)
      - R-Z (Box 7, Folder 270-274)
    - Correspondence: chronological sequence
      - Misc. Correspondence, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 275-276)
      - Thank Yous, 1983 Sep-Dec (Box 7, Folder 277)
      - Misc. Correspondence 1, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 278-279)
      - Misc. Correspondence, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 280-283)
      - Thank Yous, 1984 Jan-Jun (Box 7, Folder 284-285)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984 May-Jun (Box 7, Folder 286-288)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984 Sep-1988 Aug (Box 8, Folder 289-293)
    - Installation
      - Installation, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 294-295)
      - Acting Dean and Installation (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - Trips
      - Texas Trip (Box 8, Folder 297)
      - California Trip, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 298)
      - Florida, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 299-300)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Report of the Review Committee (Box 8, Folder 301)
      - Re: new Students, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 302)
      - Development (Box 8, Folder 303)
      - Incoming Students, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 304)
      - Job Openings, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 305)
      - Student Resumes (Box 8, Folder 306)
      - Misc. "Filing" (Box 8, Folder 307)
      - Church, Kortright (Box 8, Folder 308)
      - Misc. Odds and Ends (Box 8, Folder 309)
      - Correspondence re: Preaching Honestly… (Box 8, Folder 310)
      - Students, Conferences, notes, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 311)
      - Students intending Lay Vocations (Box 8, Folder 312)
      - Guidelines for New Dean (Box 8, Folder 313)
      - Job Seekers (Box 8, Folder 314)
      - EP Survey (Box 8, Folder 315)
      - Engagements (Box 8, Folder 316)
      - Alumni Fund printout, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 317)
      - Personal File, 1969-1991 (Box 8, Folder 317b-317c)
  - Philip Turner, 1991-1998
    - Installation (Box 8, Folder 318-320)
    - Misc. (Box 8, Folder 321)
  - William Franklin, 1998-2001
    - Installation (Box 8, Folder 322)
    - Misc (Box 8, Folder 323)
  - List of Deans, 1942-1991 (Box 8, Folder 324)
- Trustees, Series II
  - Individual Member Files, 1923-1986
    - Buckman, Mr. John W. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Burlingham, C. C. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Credick, Nowell (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Donegan, Harold (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ford, Rev. C. Allan (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Fox, Heywood (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Galpin, Samuel (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Gibson, Nell (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Gulden, Frank (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Lawrence, Charles and Margaret (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Lorimer, Linda (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - McLean, Mr. Robert III (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Martiner, Rev. John W. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Morton, Rt. Rev. C. Brinkley (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Plant, John (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Razee, Rev. George W. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Red, John W. Jr. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Robbins, Walter S. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Robbins, Rev. William (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Robinson, Very Rev. Dillard (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Rodman, Edward (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Rogers, Rev. E. Page (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Stetson, Charles (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Student Trustees (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Sonne, Christian R. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Thompsett, Dr. Fredrica H. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Whiteman, Harold
      - General (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence with Michael Allen (Box 9, Folder 28-30)
      - Correspondence with Rowan Greer (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence with Charles Clark (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - 1975 Report (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence with Anderson (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Williams, Mr. E. Thomas Jr. (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Van Culin, Rev. Samuel Jr. (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Minutes and Meetings
    - Minutes Book, 1854-1901 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1870-1893 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1894-1923 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1900-1921 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1921-1946 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book (Board of Overseers), 1926-1942 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1947-1965 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Book, 1965-1973 (Box 10)
    - Minutes Books Inserts, 1894-1923 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Minutes Books Inserts, 1900-1921 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Minutes Books Inserts (Board of Overseers), 1926-1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Meeting Materials Communications, 1958 Jan (Box 11, Folder 39b)
      - Meeting Materials Communications, 1926-1964 (Box 11, Folder 39c)
      - Meeting Materials Communications, 1963-1969 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Deans Reports to the Board, 1921-1952 (Box 11)
    - Deans Reports to the Board, 1957-1967 (Box 11)
    - Meeting Materials, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 40-42)
    - Meeting Materials, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 43-45)
    - Meeting Materials, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 46-47)
    - Meeting Materials, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 48-50)
    - Minutes Books, 1974-1979 (Box 11)
    - Meeting Materials Communications, 1974-1978 (Box 11, Folder 51-55)
    - Minutes Books, 1979-1986 (Box 12)
    - Minutes Books, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Meeting Materials Communications, 1980-1986 (Box 12, Folder 56b-67)
    - Minutes Books, 1979-1986 (Box 12)
    - Meeting Materials Communications, 1987 -1990 (Box 12, Folder 68-74)
    - Agendas, 1973-1991 (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Minutes Books, 1991-1997 (Box 13)
    - Minutes, Drafts/Copies, 1932-2001 (Box 13, Folder 76-91)
    - Deans Reports to the Board, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Deans Reports to the Board, 1975-1991 (Box 13, Folder 93-96)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Memos Correspondence, 1964-1992 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - Financial Crisis, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 98)
    - Miscellanous Documents (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - Merger Study (Box 13, Folder 100)
    - Affiliation Agreement, 1985, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 101)
    - Financial, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 102)
    - Association of Governing Boards, 1981-1991 (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - Honorary Degree Citations, 1964-1990 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - Tributes (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - Trustees Fellowship, 1973, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Board of Permanent Officers, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Elections/Resignations, 1973-1990 (Box 14, Folder 108)
  - Charter Bylaws
    - Various, 1908-1988, no date (Box 14, Folder 109-112)
  - Financial
    - Treasurer's File, 1957-1974 (Box 14, Folder 113-114)
    - Budget, 1975-1991 (Box 14, Folder 115-116)
    - Trustees Annual Fund, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 117-118)
    - Charts of Accounts (Box 14, Folder 119)
    - Audits
    - Audits, 1974, 1978-1980, 1982-1985, 1987, 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 120-123)
  - Committees
    - Executive Committee, 1970-1987 (Box 14, Folder 124-133)
    - Building Grounds, 1924-1941, 1963-1970, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 134-136)
    - Dean Search, 1969-1970, 1982, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 137-139)
    - Dean Review, 1975, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 140-141)
    - Development, 1972-1988 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Education, 1932-1986 (Box 15, Folder 143-149)
    - Finance, 1930-1985 (Box 15, Folder 150-156)
    - Degrees, 1971-1991 (Box 15, Folder 157-168)
    - Degrees: Recipient Lists, 1922-1991 (Box 15, Folder 169)
    - Degrees: Programs, 1987-1990 (Box 15, Folder 170)
    - Investment, 1977-1988 (Box 16, Folder 171-172)
    - Planning, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Membership
    - Nominations, 1935-1990 (Box 16, Folder 174-185)
    - Letters of Acceptance/Resignation, 1929-1959 (Box 16, Folder 186-188)
    - Lists, 1968-1991 (Box 16, Folder 189-196)
    - Yale Trustees, 1973-1990 (Box 16, Folder 197)
    - Alumni Trustees, 1979-1991 (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - Faculty Trustees, 1974-1994 (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - Officers, 1985-1991 (Box 16, Folder 200)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1976 (Box 16, Folder 201-205)
    - Advisory Council to YDS Dean, 1979-1982, no date. (Box 16, Folder 206-210)
  - BDS Feasibility Study, 1969 (Box 16)
- Faculty Staff, Series III
  - Faculty Files
    - Anderson, Robert, 1978-1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Barbour, J.H., 1887 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Batten, Charles (1958) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Belshaw, Harold (1937-1951) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Brown, F. Craighill (1953-1966), 1952-1967 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
    - Burgess, John (1976-1979), 1972-1983 (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
    - Carr, Burgess (1982-1985), 1981-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Cheney, Francis, 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Cook, Elmer (1943-1959), 1942-1968 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Denton, Robert, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Diekmann, Richard (1978-1979), 1978-1981 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Gardiner, Frederic, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Herrick, Charles, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Hardy, Edward (1944-1969)
      - Master's Thesis, 1924 (Box 17)
      - Files, 1929-1969 (Box 17, Folder 17-26)
      - Files, 1970-1982, no date (Box 18, Folder 27-28)
      - Notes on the Ritualistic Controversy in America (Box 18, Folder 29)
      - Notes on Church History (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Photographs (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Hicks, Lansing, 1953-1982 (Box 18, Folder 32-34)
    - James, Fleming (1921-1940), 1921-1946 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Jeschke, Channing (1966-1971) (Box 18, Folder 36)